OK, so today I want to talk about how we talk about love.
حسنًا، أودّ اليوم الحديث حول كيف نتكلّم عن الحب.
And specifically,
وتحديدًا،
I want to talk about what's wrong with how we talk about love.
أوّد التكلّم عن الخطأ بحديثنا عن الحب.
Most of us will probably fall in love a few times
ربما أغلبنا سيقع بالحب عدة مرات
over the course of our lives,
على مدى حياتنا،
and in the English language, this metaphor, falling,
وباللغة الإنجليزية، هذا التعبير المجازي، الوقوع،
is really the main way that we talk about that experience.
هو بالواقع الطريقة الرئيسيّة الّتي نتحدّث بها عن تلك التّجربة.
I don't know about you,
لا أعرف عنكم،
but when I conceptualize this metaphor,
ولكن عندما أتخيّل هذا التعبير،
what I picture is straight out of a cartoon --
ما أتصوّره يأتي من رسم متحرك--
like there's a man,
كأنّ هناك رجل،
he's walking down the sidewalk,
يمشي على الرصيف،
without realizing it, he crosses over an open manhole,
بدون أن ينتبه، يعبر على حفرة مفتوحة،
and he just plummets into the sewer below.
وما لبث أن سقط في قناة المجاري بالأسفل
And I picture it this way because falling is not jumping.
وأتصوّر ذلك بهذه الطريقة لأن الوقوع ليس قفز.
Falling is accidental,
الوقوع هو غير مقصود،
it's uncontrollable.
لا يمكن التحكّم به.
It's something that happens to us without our consent.
إنّه أمرٌ يحدث لنا بدون موافقتنا.
And this --
وهذه --
this is the main way we talk about starting a new relationship.
هي الطريقة الأساسيّة لحديثنا عن بدء علاقة جديدة.
I am a writer and I'm also an English teacher,
إنّني كاتبة ومدرّسة لغة إنجليزية أيضًا،
which means I think about words for a living.
ما يعني أنّني أفكر بالكلمات لأكسب عيشي.
You could say that I get paid to argue that the language we use matters,
يمكنك القول بأنّني أتقاضى لأقول بأن اللغة الّتي نستخدمها هي ذات أهميّة،
and I would like to argue that many of the metaphors we use
وأودّ القول بأن العديد من التعابير المجازية التي نستخدمها
to talk about love --
للحديث عن الحب --
maybe even most of them --
ربما حتّى أغلبها --
are a problem.
هي مشكلة.
So, in love, we fall.
إذاً، بالحب، نحن نقع.
We're struck.
نصطدم.
We are crushed.
نُسحق.
We swoon.
نفقد الوعي.
We burn with passion.
نُحرق شغفًا
Love makes us crazy,
يجعلنا الحب مجانين،
and it makes us sick.
يجعلنا مرضى.
Our hearts ache,
يؤلم قلوبنا،
and then they break.
ويكسرها لاحقًا.
So our metaphors equate the experience of loving someone
إذًا تعادل تعابيرنا المجازية تجربة حب شخص ما
to extreme violence or illness.
بعنفٍ شديد أو لدرجة المرض.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
They do.
إنّها كذلك.
And they position us as the victims
وهي تضعنا بموقف الضحايا
of unforeseen and totally unavoidable circumstances.
لظروفٍ غير متوقعة ولا مفرّ منها إطلاقًا.
My favorite one of these is "smitten,"
المفضّل بالنسبة لي منها هو "مُغرم"
which is the past participle of the word "smite."
والذي هو اسم الفاعل من كلمة "غُرم."
And if you look this word up in the dictionary --
وإذا بحثت عن هذه الكلمة في القاموس--
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
you will see that it can be defined as both "grievous affliction,"
سترى بأنّه يمكن تعريفها بكلّ من "حزن شديد،"
and, "to be very much in love."
و"حالة الحب الشديد."
I tend to associate the word "smite" with a very particular context,
وأميل لربط كلمة "غٌرم" مع سياقٍ خاصٍ جدًّا،
which is the Old Testament.
الّذي هو العهد القديم.
In the Book of Exodus alone, there are 16 references to smiting,
في كتاب سفر الخروج وحده، هناك 16 دلالة للغرام،
which is the word that the Bible uses for the vengeance of an angry God.
والّتي هي الكلمة التي يستخدمها الإنجيل لنقمة إله غاضب.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Here we are using the same word to talk about love
نحن هنا نستخدم الكلمة ذاتها بالحديث عن الحب
that we use to explain a plague of locusts.
بالّتي نستخدمها لشرح آفة الجراد.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Right?
أليس كذلك؟
So, how did this happen?
إذًا، كيف حدث ذلك؟
How have we come to associate love with great pain and suffering?
كيف وصلنا لربط الحب بالألم العظيم والمعاناة؟
And why do we talk about this ostensibly good experience
ولماذا نتحدث عن هذه التجربة الجميلة ظاهريًّا
as if we are victims?
كما لو أنّنا ضحايا؟
These are difficult questions,
إنّها أسئلةٌ صعبة
but I have some theories.
لكن لدي بعض النظريات.
And to think this through,
والّتي من خلالها،
I want to focus on one metaphor in particular,
أريد التركيز على تعبيرٍ مجازيٍّ معين،
which is the idea of love as madness.
والّذي هو فكرة الحب كالجنون.
When I first started researching romantic love,
عندما بدأت البحث عن الحب الرومانسي للمرة الأولى،
I found these madness metaphors everywhere.
وجدت تعابير الجنون هذه في كلّ مكان.
The history of Western culture
تاريخ الثقافة الغربية
is full of language that equates love to mental illness.
حافل بكلمات تربط الحب بالمرض العقلي.
These are just a few examples.
هذه فقط بعض الأمثلة.
William Shakespeare:
وليم شكسبير قال:
"Love is merely a madness,"
"الحب هو مجرد جنون،"
from "As You Like It."
بمسرحية "كما تشاء."
Friedrich Nietzsche:
فريدريك نيتشه قال:
"There is always some madness in love."
"هناك دائمًا بعض الجنون في الحب."
"Got me looking, got me looking so crazy in love -- "
"جعلتني أبدو، جعلتني أبدو مجنونة جدًّا بالحب--"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
from the great philosopher, Beyoncé Knowles.
للفيلسوفة العظيمة، بيونسيه نولز
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I fell in love for the first time when I was 20,
وقعتُ في الحب للمرة الأولى عندما كنت بالـ20 من العمر،
and it was a pretty turbulent relationship right from the start.
وكانت علاقة مضطربة للغاية منذ البداية.
And it was long distance for the first couple of years,
وكانت المسافة بعيدة بأول عامين،
so for me that meant very high highs and very low lows.
لذا كان هذا بالنسبة لي معناه اللحظات الجميلة جميلة جدًا والحزينة حزينة جدًا.
I can remember one moment in particular.
أستطيع تَذكُّر لحظة واحدة على وجه الخصوص.
I was sitting on a bed in a hostel in South America,
كنت جالسة على السرير في نزُل بأمريكا الجنوبية،
and I was watching the person I love walk out the door.
وكنت أشاهد الشخص الذي أُحب يخرج من الباب.
And it was late,
وكان الوقت متأخّرًا
it was nearly midnight,
حوالي منتصف اللّيل،
we'd gotten into an argument over dinner,
كنا قد خضنا جدالًا على طاولة العشاء،
and when we got back to our room,
وعندما عدنا إلى غرفتنا،
he threw his things in the bag and stormed out.
رمى أغراضه في حقيبة وخرج.
While I can no longer remember what that argument was about,
بينما لم أعد أستطيع تذكّر سبب ذاك الجدال،
I very clearly remember how I felt watching him leave.
أتذكّر بشكلٍ واضحٍ جدًّا كيف كان شعوري وأنا أراه يغادر.
I was 22, it was my first time in the developing world,
كان عمري 22، وكانت المرة الأولى لي في العالم النامي،
and I was totally alone.
وكنت وحيدة تمامًا.
I had another week until my flight home,
كان لدي أسبوع آخر حتّى موعد طائرة عودتي،
and I knew the name of the town that I was in,
وكنت أعرف اسم البلدة التي كنت بها،
and the name of the city that I needed to get to to fly out,
واسم المدينة التي كان يجب علي الوصول إليها لكي أسافر عبرها إلى الخارج،
but I had no idea how to get around.
لكن ليس لدي أدنى فكرة عن كيفية الوصول إليها.
I had no guidebook and very little money,
لم يكن لدي كتيب إرشادي والقليل جدًّا من المال،
and I spoke no Spanish.
ولم أتكلّم الإسبانيّة.
Someone more adventurous than me
شخصٌ ما أكثر مغامرةً منّي
might have seen this as a moment of opportunity,
ربما يعتبر ذلك كفرصة،
but I just froze.
لكنّي كنت فعلًا مشلولة.
I just sat there.
كنت قد جلست هناك.
And then I burst into tears.
وانفجرت بعدها من البكاء.
But despite my panic,
لكن على الرغم من فزعي،
some small voice in my head thought,
بعض الأصوات في رأسي كانت تقول،
"Wow. That was dramatic.
"واو. كان ذلك دراماتيكيًا
I must really be doing this love thing right."
لابد أنني أمارس الحب بشكلٍ جيد للغاية."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Because some part of me wanted to feel miserable in love.
لأن بعضًا منّي كان يريد شعورًا بائسًا في الحب.
And it sounds so strange to me now, but at 22,
وهذا يبدو غريبًا جدًّا بالنسبة لي حاليًّا، لكن في عمر الـ22،
I longed to have dramatic experiences,
كنت أتوق لأعيش تجارب مثيرة،
and in that moment, I was irrational and furious and devastated,
وفي تلك اللحظة، كنت غير عقلانية وغاضبة ومدمّرة،
and weirdly enough,
وبشكلٍ غريبٍ جدًا،
I thought that this somehow legitimized the feelings I had
ظننت بطريقة أو بأخرى أنّ شعوري حيال الفتى
for the guy who had just left me.
الذي كان قد تركني للتو كان مبررًا.
I think on some level I wanted to feel a little bit crazy,
أعتقد أنّي أردت الشعور بأنّني مجنونة قليلًا إلى حدٍّ ما،
because I thought that that was how love worked.
لأنني ظننت أنه هكذا يجب أن يكون الحب.
This really should not be surprising,
لا ينبغي حقًّا أن يكون هذا مفاجئًا،
considering that according to Wikipedia,
على اعتبار أنّه وفقًا لويكيبيديا،
there are eight films,
هناك ثمانية أفلام،
14 songs,
و 14 أغنية،
two albums and one novel with the title "Crazy Love."
وألبومين ورواية بعنوان "الحب المجنون".
About half an hour later, he came back to our room.
بعد حوالي نصف ساعة، عاد إلى غرفتنا.
We made up.
تصالحنا.
We spent another mostly happy week traveling together.
قضينا أسبوعًا آخر سعيد نوعًا ما بالسفر معًا.
And then, when I got home,
بعد ذلك، عندما وصلت إلى الديار
I thought, "That was so terrible and so great.
فكرت، "كان ذلك رهيبًا وعظيمًا جدًا.
This must be a real romance."
لابد أنّها قصة حبٍ حقيقيّة."
I expected my first love to feel like madness,
كنت أتوقع أن أشعر بحبّي الأول وكأنّه جنون،
and of course, it met that expectation very well.
وبالتأكيد، لقد تحقق ذلك التوقع تمامًا.
But loving someone like that --
لكن محبّة شخصٍ هكذا --
as if my entire well-being depended on him loving me back --
كما لو أنّ سعادتي بأكملها متوقفة على محبته المقابلة لي --
was not very good for me
لم تكن مناسبة بالنسبة لي
or for him.
أو له.
But I suspect this experience of love is not that unusual.
ولكن أظن أنّ تجربة الحب هذه ليست غريبة.
Most of us do feel a bit mad in the early stages of romantic love.
معظمنا يشعر بالجنون بعض الشيء في المراحل الأولى من الحب الرومانسي.
In fact, there is research to confirm that this is somewhat normal,
في الواقع، هناك دراسة تؤكد أن هذا الأمر طبيعي إلى حدٍ ما،
because, neurochemically speaking,
لأنه، من منظور الكيمياء العصبية،
romantic love and mental illness are not that easily distinguished.
الحب الرومانسي والمرض العقلي لا يتم تفريقهما بسهولة.
This is true.
هذا صحيح.
This study from 1999 used blood tests
استخدمت هذه الدراسة منذ عام 1999 تحاليل الدم
to confirm that the serotonin levels of the newly in love
للتأكيد على أن مستويات السيروتونين للذين يمرون بعلاقة حب جديدة
very closely resembled the serotonin levels
تقارب بدرجة كبيرة مستويات السيروتونين
of people who had been diagnosed with obsessive-compulsive disorder.
للناس الذين تم تشخيص حالاتهم باضطراب الوسواس القهري.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Yes, and low levels of serotonin
أجل، ويرتبط انخفاض مستويات السيروتونين
are also associated with seasonal affective disorder
أيضًا مع الاضطرابات العاطفية الموسمية والاكتئاب.
So there is some evidence
حتّى أنّه هناك بعض الأدلة
that love is associated with changes to our moods and our behaviors.
أن الحب يرتبط مع تغيّرات حالاتنا المزاجية وتصرفاتنا.
And there are other studies to confirm
وهناك دراسات أخرى تؤكد
that most relationships begin this way.
بأنّ معظم العلاقات تبدأ بهذه الطريقة.
Researchers believe that the low levels of serotonin
يرى الباحثون أن انخفاض مستويات السيروتونين
is correlated with obsessive thinking about the object of love,
يرتبط بالتفكير الاستحواذي حول موضوع الحب،
which is like this feeling that someone has set up camp in your brain.
الذي يشبه الشعور بأن شخصاً ما قد أنشأ معسكرًا في دماغك.
And most of us feel this way when we first fall in love.
ويشعر معظمنا بهذه الطريقة عندما نقع في الحب للمرة الأولى.
But the good news is, it doesn't always last that long --
لكن الخبر السار هو أن ذلك ا يستمر طويلًا --
usually from a few months to a couple of years.
من بضعة أشهر إلى سنتين عادةً.
When I got back from my trip to South America,
عندما عدت من رحلتي إلى أمريكا الجنوبية،
I spent a lot of time alone in my room,
قضيت الكثير من الوقت وحيدةً في غرفتي،
checking my email,
أتحقق من بريدي الإلكتروني،
desperate to hear from the guy I loved.
مستميتةً لردٍّ من الفتى الذّي أحببت.
I decided that if my friends could not understand my grievous affliction,
قررتُ أنه إذا لم يتفهّم أصدقائي محنتي الشديدة،
then I did not need their friendship.
إذًا لست بحاجة إلى صداقتهم.
So I stopped hanging out with most of them.
لذلك توقّفت عن التسكّع مع معظمهم.
And it was probably the most unhappy year of my life.
وربما كان ذلك العام الأكثر تعاسة من حياتي.
But I think I felt like it was my job to be miserable,
ولكنّي أعتقد أنني شعرت أنه كان عملي أن أكون بائسة،
because if I could be miserable,
لأنه إذا أمكنني أن أكون بائسة،
then I would prove how much I loved him.
سأثبت كم أحبّه.
And if I could prove it,
وإذا كان بإمكاني إثبات ذلك،
then we would have to end up together eventually.
إذًا سنكون معًا في نهاية المطاف.
This is the real madness,
هذا هو الجنون الحقيقي،
because there is no cosmic rule
لأنه لا يوجد قاعدة كونية
that says that great suffering equals great reward,
تقول بأن المعاناة تستحق أجرًا عظيمًا
but we talk about love as if this is true.
لكننا نتحدث عن الحب كما لو أنّه حقيقيًا.
Our experiences of love are both biological and cultural.
تجاربنا في الحب هي بيولوجيّة وثقافيّة على حدٍّ سواء
Our biology tells us that love is good
تخبرنا البيولوجيا أنّ الحب أمرٌ جيد
by activating these reward circuits in our brain,
من خلال تنشيط دوائر المكافأة هذه في الدماغ،
and it tells us that love is painful when, after a fight or a breakup,
يخبرنا أن الحب هو مؤلم عندما، بعد شجار أو انفصال،
that neurochemical reward is withdrawn.
يتم سحب المكافأة الكيميائية العصبية.
And in fact -- and maybe you've heard this --
وفي الواقع -- ولعلّكم سمعتم هذا --
neurochemically speaking,
من منظور الكيميائية العصبية،
going through a breakup is a lot like going through cocaine withdrawal,
الانفصال شبيه جدًّا بسحب الكوكايين،
which I find reassuring.
الّذي أجده مطَمئنًا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And then our culture uses language
ومن ثم تستخدم ثقافتنا لغة
to shape and reinforce these ideas about love.
لتشكيل وتعزيز هذه الأفكار عن الحب.
In this case, we're talking about metaphors about pain
في هذه الحالة، نحن نتحدث عن تعابير الألم
and addiction and madness.
والإدمان والجنون.
It's kind of an interesting feedback loop.
إنّها نوع من رد الفعل مثير للاهتمام.
Love is powerful and at times painful,
الحب قوي ومؤلم أحيانًا،
and we express this in our words and stories,
ونعبّر عن هذا في كلماتنا وقصصنا،
but then our words and stories prime us
ولكن بعد ذلك كلماتنا وقصصنا تقودنا
to expect love to be powerful and painful.
لتوقّع أن يكون الحب قويًا ومؤلمًا.
What's interesting to me is that all of this happens
المثير للاهتمام بالنسبة لي هو أن هذا كلّه يحدث
in a culture that values lifelong monogamy.
في الثقافة التي تقدّر الزواج الوحيد المستمر مدى الحياة.
It seems like we want it both ways:
يبدو الأمر كما لو أننا نريد كلا الاتجاهين:
we want love to feel like madness,
نريد الحب لنشعر بالجنون،
and we want it to last an entire lifetime.
ونريده أن يستمر العمر كلّه.
That sounds terrible.
يبدو هذا فظيعًا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
To reconcile this,
لإصلاح ذلك،
we need to either change our culture or change our expectations.
نحن بحاجة إمّا إلى تغيير ثقافتنا أو تغيير توقعاتنا.
So, imagine if we were all less passive in love.
لذلك، تخيّلوا لو كنا جميعًا أقل سلبيّة في الحب.
If we were more assertive, more open-minded, more generous
إذا كنا أكثر حزمًا، وأكثر انفتاحًا، وأكثر سخاءً
and instead of falling in love,
وبدلًا من الوقوع في الحب،
we stepped into love.
نصعد إلى الحب.
I know that this is asking a lot,
أعلم أن ذلك يتطلب الكثير،
but I'm not actually the first person to suggest this.
ولكنّي لست في الواقع أول شخص يقترح ذلك.
In their book, "Metaphors We Live By,"
في كتابهما "التعابير المجازية التي نعيش بها"،
linguists Mark Johnson and George Lakoff suggest a really interesting solution
عرض اللغويّان مارك جونسون وجورج لاكوف حلاً مهمًا للغاية
to this dilemma,
لهذه المعضلة،
which is to change our metaphors.
وهو تغيير تعابيرنا المجازية.
They argue that metaphors really do shape the way we experience the world,
يقولان أن التعابير في الواقع تشكّل الطريقة التي نواجه بها العالم،
and that they can even act as a guide for future actions,
وأنها يمكن أن تعمل حتى كدليل للأعمال المستقبليّة،
like self-fulfilling prophecies.
كنبوءات ذاتية التحقيق.
Johnson and Lakoff suggest a new metaphor for love:
اقترح جونسون ولاكوف تعبيرًا مجازيًا جديدًا للحب:
love as a collaborative work of art.
الحب كعمل فنّي مشترك.
I really like this way of thinking about love.
إنّني حقًّا أحبّ هذه الطريقة للتفكير بالحب.
Linguists talk about metaphors as having entailments,
تحدّث اللغويّان عن التعابير المجازية كامتلاك موروثات،
which is essentially a way of considering all the implications of,
والتي هي في جوهرها وسيلة للنظر في جميع الآثار المترتبة،
or ideas contained within, a given metaphor.
أو الأفكار الواردة في تعبير مجازي معين.
And Johnson and Lakoff talk about everything
وتحدّث جونسون ولاكوف عن كل
that collaborating on a work of art entails:
ما يتطلّب هذا العمل الفنّي المشترك:
effort, compromise, patience, shared goals.
الجهد، الوفاق، والصبر، والأهداف المشتركة.
These ideas align nicely with our cultural investment
هذه الأفكار تلائم الاستثمار الثقافي لدينا بشكلٍ جيد
in long-term romantic commitment,
في الالتزام الرومانسي طويل الأجل،
but they also work well for other kinds of relationships --
كما أنّها تعمل بشكل جيد لأنواع أخرى من العلاقات --
short-term, casual, polyamorous, non-monogamous, asexual --
قصيرة الأجل، العارضة، المفتوحة، غير الأحاديّة، اللاجنسية --
because this metaphor brings much more complex ideas
لأن هذا التعبير يجلب أفكارًا أكثر تعقيدًا بكثير
to the experience of loving someone.
لتجربة محبة شخص ما.
So if love is a collaborative work of art,
فإذا كان الحب هو عمل فنيّ مشترك،
then love is an aesthetic experience.
إذًا الحب هو تجربة جماليّة.
Love is unpredictable,
الحب لا يمكن التنبؤ به،
love is creative,
الحب خلّاق،
love requires communication and discipline,
يتطلّب الحب التواصل والانضباط،
it is frustrating and emotionally demanding.
إنّه محبط ومتطلّب عاطفيًا.
And love involves both joy and pain.
ويتضمن الحب كلًّا من السعادة والألم.
Ultimately, each experience of love is different.
بالنهاية، كل تجربة حب هي مختلفة.
When I was younger,
عندما كنت أصغر سنًا،
it never occurred to me that I was allowed to demand more from love,
لم يحدث قط أن أُتيح لي طلب المزيد من الحب،
that I didn't have to just accept whatever love offered.
حتى أنّه لم يكن يجدر بي قبول أيّ حب مقدّم.
When 14-year-old Juliet first meets --
عندما تقابل جولييت البالغة من العمر 14 عاماً لأول مرة -
or, when 14-year-old Juliet cannot be with Romeo,
أو، عندما لا يمكن لجولييت ذات الـ 14 عاماً أن تكون مع روميو،
whom she has met four days ago,
الذي كانت قد التقته قبل أربعة أيام،
she does not feel disappointed or angsty.
إنّها لا تشعر بخيبة أمل أو بقلق.
Where is she?
أين هي؟
She wants to die.
إنها تريد أن تموت.
Right?
حقًا؟
And just as a refresher, at this point in the play,
وكتجديد، في هذه المرحلة في المسرحية،
act three of five,
الفصل الثالث من أصل خمسة،
Romeo is not dead.
روميو لم يمت.
He's alive,
كان حيًا،
he's healthy,
إنه بصحة جيدة،
he's just been banished from the city.
لقد تم نفيه من المدينة فقط.
I understand that 16th-century Verona is unlike contemporary North America,
إني أدرك أن فيرونا في القرن الـ16 على خلاف أمريكا الشمالية الحديثة،
and yet when I first read this play,
ولكن عندما قرأت لأول مرة هذه المسرحية،
also at age 14,
عندما كنت في سن الـ 14 أيضاً،
Juliet's suffering made sense to me.
معاناة جولييت كانت منطقية بالنسبة لي.
Reframing love as something I get to create with someone I admire,
إعادة صياغة الحب كشيء أتمكّن من خلقه مع شخص معجبة به،
rather than something that just happens to me
وليس كشيءٍ يحدث لي
without my control or consent,
دون إرادتي أو موافقتي،
is empowering.
هو شيءٌ مشجع.
It's still hard.
ما زال صعبًا.
Love still feels totally maddening and crushing some days,
ما يزال الحب يبدو جنونيًا تمامًا ومحطِّمًا بعض الأيام،
and when I feel really frustrated,
وعندما أشعر بالإحباط حقًا،
I have to remind myself:
لا بد لي أن أذكّر نفسي:
my job in this relationship is to talk to my partner
عملي في هذه العلاقة هو أن أتحدث إلى شريكي
about what I want to make together.
حول ما أريد فعله معًا.
This isn't easy, either.
هذا ليس بالأمر السهل، أيضًا.
But it's just so much better than the alternative,
ولكنّه أفضل بكثير من البديل،
which is that thing that feels like madness.
الذي هو ذلك الشيء الذي يبدو كالجنون.
This version of love is not about winning or losing someone's affection.
هذه النسخة من الحب ليست عن فوز أو خسارة مودة شخص ما.
Instead, it requires that you trust your partner
بل، إنها تتطلّب أن تثق بشريك حياتك
and talk about things when trusting feels difficult,
والحديث عن الأشياء عندما تكون الثقة صعبة،
which sounds so simple,
التي تبدو في غاية البساطة،
but is actually a kind of revolutionary, radical act.
ولكنها في الواقع نوعاً ما فعل ثوريّ متطرف.
This is because you get to stop thinking about yourself
وذلك لأنك تتوقف عن التفكير في نفسك
and what you're gaining or losing in your relationship,
وماذا تكتسب أو تخسر في علاقتك،
and you get to start thinking about what you have to offer.
وتبدأ في التفكير في ما لديك لتقدمه.
This version of love allows us to say things like,
هذه النسخة من الحب تتيح لنا أن نقول أشياء مثل،
"Hey, we're not very good collaborators. Maybe this isn't for us."
"مهلاً، إنّنا لسنا متعاونين جيدًا. ربما هذا ليس لنا."
Or, "That relationship was shorter than I had planned,
أو "كانت تلك العلاقة أقصر مما كنت قد خططت،
but it was still kind of beautiful."
ولكنها مازالت جميلة."
The beautiful thing about the collaborative work of art
الشيء الجميل حول العمل الفنّي التعاوني
is that it will not paint or draw or sculpt itself.
هو أنه لن يلوّن أو يرسم أو ينحت نفسه.
This version of love allows us to decide what it looks like.
هذه النسخة من الحب تتيح لنا نحن أن نقرر ما يبدو عليه.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)